Sparks Photographs
undated
- Photographs, 1860-1997
  - Girl laying on a bed, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1838; Photographic print; 3 1/2 x 2 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a young girl wearing a striped dress. She is laying on a bed with her head resting on some pillows. No identification.
  - Woman and girl standing in front of a window, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1839; Photographic print; 3 x 5 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a woman and girl standing in front of a window. The woman has her arm around the girl and is smiling at the camera. The girl is looking to the right and pouting. No identification.
  - Five month baby sitting on a couch, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1840; Photographic print; 3 1/8 x 4 1/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a baby sitting on a striped couch. The baby is dressed in a white garment. Handwritten on verso: 5 mo. No identification.
  - Two men standing in a field, June 26, 1911; UNRS-P2017-13_1841; Photographic print; 5 1/2 x 3 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of two men standing between two fields leaning against shovels. The field in front is plowed without any vegetation growing yet and the field in back has some vegetation growing. Handwritten on verso: June 26, 1911. No identification.
  - Unidentified woman and Maud Sparks MacKenzie in a motorcar, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1842; Photographic print; 3 3/8 x 5 3/8 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Postcard from a photograph of two women sitting in a motorcar. Both are wearing dark dresses and hats. The woman on the right may be Maud Sparks MacKenzie. Postcard.
  - Man on horseback, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1843; Photographic print; 3 5/8 x 4 5/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a man on horseback with the horse facing away from the camera. The man is turned looking back toward the camera. In the background is a couple of men branding a calf and a wooden ranch building. No identification.
  - Horse with a trainer in front of stables, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1844; Photographic print; 3 x 4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a horse with a trainer in front of it holding a bridle lead. Behind the horse are some stables. Possibly taken at the Sparks Alamo ranch in Reno, Nevada. No identification.
  - Unidentified woman leaning against a bannister, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1845; Photographic print; 2 1/4 x 4 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of an unidentified young woman posing for the camera by leaning against the banister of an external stairway to a wooden house.
  - Woman laying on her side in the grass, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1846; Albumen print; 4 1/8 x 3 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Albumen print of an unidentified young woman in a white dress. She is laying on a blanket and pillow in a yard with a fence in the background. No identification.
  - Woman standing in front of a tree, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1847; Photographic print; 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a woman wearing a white dress and a hat with flowers and ribbons to tie under her chin. She is standing in front of a tree. No identification.
    The woman in photographs 01847 and 01848 is the same woman.
  - Woman standing in front of some bushes, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1848; Photographic print; 3 1/4 x 4 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a woman in a white dress and a hat with flowers and ribbons to tie under her chin standing next to a bush. She is holding one of the branches and smiling at the camera. No identification.
  - Man on horseback at the base of a hill, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1849; Photographic print; 3 5/8 x 4 5/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of an unidentified man in ranching clothes sitting on horseback. Behind him is a hill covered in sagebrush.
  - Two men outside a warehouse, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1850; Postcard; 3 3/8 x 5 3/8 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Postcard from a photograph of two unidentified men outside of a metal warehouse. One of the men is sitting on a box wearing a suit and tie. The other man is leaning on the box with one of his legs swung over the first man's leg and his arm on the first man's shoulder. Possibly some fraternity brothers of Charles Sparks.
  - Field with trees at the edge, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1851; Photographic print; 6 x 4 1/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of a field of sagebrush with trees in the middle ground. In the background are some mountains. Stamped on verso: Print by Crandall's Palo Alto, Calif.
  - Mountains at the edge of a field, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1852; Photographic print; 6 1/8 x 4 1/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Men, horses, and a dog on a hillside in front of a valley, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1853; Photographic print; 6 x 4 1/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of five men, two horses, and a dog standing in a field of sagebrush. Four of the men are standing and one man is riding the left horse. Both horses are laden with bundles of provisions. In the background are mountains. Stamped on verso: Print by Crandall's Palo Alto, Calif.
  - Unidentified man, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1854; Albumen print; 1 3/8 x 1 7/8 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Albumen print of an unidentified man with a center part in his hair, a mustache, and wearing a suit with a tie. He is on the right side of the image looking up and to the left at something.
    The man in 01854 and 01855 are the same man.
  - Unidentified man, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1855; Albumen print; 1 3/8 x 1 7/8 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Albumen print of an unidentified man with part on the right side of his head and the hair curled away from the part, a mustache, and wearing a suit with a tie. He has his arms crossed in front of him and is looking directly at the camera.
    The man in 01854 and 10855 are the same man
  - Unidentified woman, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1856; Photographic print; 2 1/4 x 4 5/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of an unidentified woman wearing a white lace shirt, striped skirt, and necklace of pearls. She has her hair pulled up and is standing in a doorway with her arms behind her back.
  - Unidentified woman, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1857; Photographic print; 2 1/4 x 4 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of an unidentified woman wearing a white dress and a string of pearls. She is leaning on the edge of a doorframe with the door open behind her and is smiling at the camera.
  - Men lounging outside Davison Realty, March 16, 1907; UNRS-P2017-13_1858; Photographic print; 5 1/8 x 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of four men sitting and standing in front of the store front for Davison Realty. Two of the men are sitting in chairs, one is leaning against a doorframe, and one is standing in front of the doorway. The store to the left is Knox & Barton Assayers and Chemists. Handwritten on verso: HeadQuarters Co. A. 25 min. Goldfield. Mar. 16-'07. No identification.
  - Three unidentified boys, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1859; Photographic print; 6 1/2 x 4 7/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photographic portrait of three boys, one about nine years old, one about five years, and one about a year old. The older boys are working button down shirts and cardigans. No identification.
  - Three women on donkeys, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1860; Albumen print; 5 1/2 x 3 1/4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Albumen print of three women on donkeys with boxes attached to the saddles. The women are wearing dresses and hats. No identification.
    Caption with image (unknown source): Goldfield ?
  - School children holding Jack-O-Lantern puppets, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1861; Photographic print; 11 1/4 x 4 7/8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of twenty-one children and one woman standing or sitting in front of a building with bushes around the door. The children are wearing paper crowns holding Jack-O-Lantern puppets. They are smiling at the camera. No identification.
  - Man and a cook in a room with mechanical equipment, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1862; Photographic print; 10 x 8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Photograph of two men in a room of mechanical equipment. One of the men is sitting at a table with a plate, cup, and milk in front of him. He is using a fork to grab some food out of a pan the second man is holding. The second man is wearing an apron and chef's hat and holding a knife and the pan. No identification.
  - John Sparks, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1863; Photographic print; 11 7/8 x 16 (Box 12)
    Oversized print of John Sparks in profile showing the left side of his face. Handwritten on front: Jno Sparks.
  - Maud Sparks holding a painting palette, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1864; Mounted photographic print; 10 1/2 x 12 5/8 (Box 12)
    Photograph of Maud Sparks wearing a dark dress with a white blouse and dark bowtie. She has her hair pulled back and is holding a palette and brushes in her left hand and mixing colors using a brush in her right hand. In the background is a floral wallpaper and a photograph hung on the wall.
  - Patricia Clarkin Spark’s grandparents, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1865; Photographic print; 12 7/8 x 10 7/8 (Box 12)
    Oversized print of Patricia Clarkin Sparks' maternal grandparents. The woman is wearing her hair pulled back and curled bangs. The man is wearing a suit and tie with a cross tie pin. He has a mustache. Handwritten on verso: Patty Clarkin-Sparks Grandparents, Mother (Delores) side.
  - Allie Burwitz Sparks sitting on a couch, circa 1992; UNRS-P2017-13_1866; Photographic print; 10 7/8 x 13 7/8 (Box 12)
    Oversized print of Allie Burwitz Sparks sitting on a couch. She is wearing a floral patterned dress and jacket. In the background are two paintings in gilded frames.
  - John Sparks, son of Benton H. Sparks, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1867; 9 7/8 x 12 7/8 (Box 12)
    Oversized portrait of John Sparks, son of Benton H. Sparks. He is wearing a tweed suit and tie and has his arms crossed. Handwritten on verso: John Sparks.
  - Jean MacKenzie on a Presbyterian missionary trip, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1868; Photographic print; 9 1/4 x 6 1/4 (Box 12)
    Mounted photograph of Jean MacKenzie in a wheeled chair being supported by to Africans. There are two other African males holding supplies in bundles on their heads. Jean is tipping a pith helmet as a sign of greeting. In the background are palm trees. Handwritten on verso: Jean MacKenzie Aunty Mauds sister in law Missionary in Africa for Presbeterian Church.
  - Maud Sparks as a young girl, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1869; Photographic print; 10 7/8 x 13 7/8 (Box 12)
    Photograph of a hand colored drawing of Maud Sparks when she was about ten years old. She is wearing a gray dress with a white lace shawl around her neck. She is looking to the left and her hair is curled with ringlets. Handwritten on verso: Picture of Auntie Maud Sparks Please return to Patsy, Lee or thier children when I no longer can use. Love Nana C. 5-16-80.
  - John Sparks sitting in profile, circa late 1860s; UNRS-P2017-13_1870; Photographic print; 10 3/4 x 13 3/4 (Box 12)
    Photograph of John Sparks sitting in a chair covered in a light blanket. He is wearing a white shirt, dark pants and vest, and a top hat. He is holding a piece of paper in his right hand and sitting facing to the right so that he is in profile. Photograph prepared by Heyn.
  - John Sparks facing the camera, circa late 1860s; UNRS-P2017-13_1871; Photographic print; 10 3/4 x 13 3/4 (Box 12)
    Photograph of John Sparks sitting in a chair covered in a light blanket. He is wearing a white shirt, dark pants and vest, and a top hat. He is holding a piece of paper in his right hand and sitting facing toward the camera looking at a point beyond the camera to the left. Photograph prepared by Heyn.
  - Men working at Sparks Alamo Ranch, November 16, 1907; UNRS-P2017-13_1872; Mounted photographic print; 10 x 8 1/8 (Box 12)
    Mounted photograph of ten men standing around a pit with wood on railroad ties. Some of the men holding wood on their shoulders. The man third from the right was John Sparks. Taken at the Sparks Alamo Ranch in Reno, Nevada. Handwritten on verso: Nov 16, 1907 Gov. Sparks Ranch, Reno, Nevada.
  - Seven men standing with a herd of horses, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1873; Mounted albumen print; 9 1/2 x 7 1/2 (Box 12)
    Mounted albumen print of seven men standing in front of a herd of horses. In the background is a log barn and a enclosed area with a herd of cattle in it. No identification.
  - Barn at Mayberry Ranch, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1874; Mounted albumen print; 9 1/2 x 7 1/2 (Box 12)
    Mounted albumen print of the barn at Mayberry Ranch west of Reno. There is a large building with a small shed attached to the front part of the barn. There are some hills in the background. Handwritten on verso: Barn at Mayberry Ranch west of Reno 5 Mi. Print prepared by C.E. Skinner of the River Side Gallery.
  - Unidentified woman working on a painting, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1875; Mounted photograohic print; 5 7/8 x 7 7/8 (Box 12)
    Mounted photograph replica of a painting of an unidentified woman sitting in front of an easel. She is holding a thin rod in her left hand, a drawing implement in her right hand, and has her right arm resting on the edge of a chair. Next to her on the ground is an open painters box.
  - John Sparks and Captain Cox riding in a parade, circa 1904; UNRS-P2017-13_1876; Mounted photographic print; 9 1/2 x 7 5/8 (Box 12)
    Photograph of Governor John Sparks (front) and Captain Cox (rear) from the Nevada State Police riding horses in what is most likely a parade. There are men standing on a sidewalk watching the governor and captain ride by on their horses. Possibly taken in Carson City, Nevada. Handwritten on verso: Gov Sparks & Capt. Cox of Nevada State Police, the horse that Sparks is riding is a Tennessee bred sadle horse.
  - Benton H. Sparks and Sidney Reeves, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1877; Photographic print; 7 x 5 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Photograph of two young men riding horses through a grassy field. Handwritten on verso in pen: Left: Leland Sparks Right: a friend of Leland. Handwritten on verso in marker: 1978 - Uncle Beenie says that this is a picture of himself & a friend Sidney Reeves of Salt Lake City. He spent a year going to school in Reno & visiting (staying) with him & the family at the family home.
  - Unprocessed Negatives, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1878 (Box 15)
    Unprocessed original negatives depicting: a ranch house (possibly the Sparks house at the Alamo ranch) around the turn of the twentieth century, people and animals, buildings at the Wedekind mine outside of Reno, Nevada. There are 48 negatives. Most are sheet film, but there are some roll film negatives.
  - Unprocessed Negatives, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1879 (Box 16)
    Unprocessed original negatives depicting: a ranch house (possibly the Sparks house at the Alamo ranch) around the turn of the twentieth century, people and animals, buildings at the Wedekind mine outside of Reno, Nevada. There are 47 negatives. Most are sheet film, but there are some roll film negatives.
  - Empty Cabinet Card Album, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1880 (Box 13)
    Album with an ornately carved leather cover. The spine has been broken and removed. Cabinet cards removed for ease of access. The inside pages have a paneled wooden finish and the album was held together with a metal clasp, which has been broken off.
    Contained photos 00150-00166.
  - Empty Cabinet Card Album, undated; UNRS-P2017-13_1881 (Box 14)
    From an album which had a faux fur cover. Cabinet cards removed for ease of access. Written at the end of the album, "Pineapple juice for diptheria, cranberries for Eyeipelas(?)"
    Contained photos 00091-00149